SHAHAB MANSOOR BAGHAEI

Sm951ja@gmail.com
9174358171
240 Ocean Parkway #3F Brooklyn New York11218

in www.linkedin/in/shahab951 https://github.com/shahab951

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic data scientist with extensive background in mathematics. Great ability for leading projects by time management, engineering expertise, collaboration and doing research. Results-focused projects by combination of different knowledges included programming, statistical analysis and machine learning.

EMPLOYMENT

New York University

Adjunct · Sept. 2015 to Current · New York

Achieve department objectives by developing course syllabi aligned with the institution's mission, values, and program outcomes. Manage the scope of creating course schedules, learning activities, lecture materials and research projects. Trained around 1000 college students regarding fundamentals of Mechanical Engineering to identify, formulate and solve complex engineering problems.

City College of New York

Industry Consultant · Feb. 2014 to Current · New York

Providing consultation, technical suggestion and support 10 industrial projects, designs, validations and implementation of industrial researches. Deliver technical method and solution based on project requirements and criteria.

EDUCATION

Springboard · Mar. 2022 to Current

Data Science

Project-Based curriculum regarding Python, programming codes, SQL, Jupyter. Studying data wrangling, EDA, data visualization, machine learning and hypothesis testing.

Post-Doctoral Fellow · Oct. 2012 to Feb. 2017

Mechanical Engineering

PhD · Jan. 2002 to Oct. 2008 Mechanical Engineering

Master · Sept. 1998 to Nov. 2000 Mechanical Engineering

SKILLS

SOFTWARE: Python (Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib), SQL, Mathematica

 $\textbf{MACHINE LEARNING:} \ Linear \ regression, \ Ridge, \ Random Forest Classifier, \ Cross \ validation, \ Logistic \ regression$

STATISTICAL ANALYSIS: Statistical parameters, Regression, Hypothesis testing

PROJECTS

Statistical analysis and prediction of reservation status for hotel booking June 2022 to July 2022

Performing data wrangling and exploratory data analysis for an extensive statistical dataset of hotel booking. Extracting some important correlations for different features and showing some statistical graphs .Proposing some functions to predict the reservation status based on model performance.

Data analysis and active driver prediction based by an appropriate model July 2022 to July 2022

Data wrangling and graph presentation of data transportation company have been performed to figure out some correlations. The active driver was predicted according to data collection by hyperparameters and appropriate n_estimator value based on model performance evaluation.

Prediction of adopted users for the project management software

Aug. 2022 to Aug. 2022

Data visualization of some important features of data frame was accomplished for the specific project management software. Adopted user for the statistical study was predicted by AdaBoostClassifier and important factors was identified for this prediction.